Now I’m going to rehearse my presentation
How do I look?
Do I look stiff?
I’m so nervous
I can tell you are nervous from the way you’re standing
Body language plays an important role in a presentation
It’s a form of non-verbal communication
I know that I can’t slouch or lean back against the wall
What else can I do to keep good posture?
Keep your back straight
and put your shoulders back
That will make you look more confident
Also, breathe smoothly
Where should I put my hands?
I shouldn’t put them in my pockets, right?
Speaking with your hands
will help keep the audience’s attention
When you use an open palm gesture
it shows that you are honest and sincere
Gestures are not only hand movements though, right?
They include movements of the head
shoulders and other parts of the body
Yes. Nodding is a good way to express your friendliness
Especially during the Q&A period
this positive gesture will encourage questions from the audience
Should I stand still behind the podium or walk around?
I tend to stare at the slides or speak to my notes when I get nervous
You can move a little but not all over the place
Remember to make eye contact
When you look people in the eye
it shows you are interested in them and have respect for them
Sometimes when an audience loses interest or isn’t paying attention
they sit back, look away or have their eyes closed
That’s the feedback you get from their body language
So, carefully watch for their responses
and quickly adjust what you’re saying
or doing to get their attention back
Thanks for the tips
I have to practice in front of a mirror
so that I’ll feel comfortable during the presentation.
That’s great
Last but not least, practice your facial expressions
You should always smile
Remember: smiling is the most powerful weapon.